Ranjini Suley

• Contact: +91 9739142279 • Email Address: suleyranjini@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Have over 16 years of experience working with the top banks in the world in various positions. Hands on with Reconciliations, Project management, Treasury Confirmations, Transaction Lifecycle Management, Exception Management, Solution design and Documentation in the BFSI domain.

OBJECTIVE

Seeking a challenging position in your esteemed organisation to fully utilize my skills and training, while making a significant contribution to the success of the company and to also be able to expand my learning, skills, and knowledge.

EDUCATION

- Currently pursuing an IBM Certified Data Science course from Learnbay, Bangalore.
- Completed a Python Full Stack Bootcamp course from Byte Academy.
- Post Graduate Diploma in Hospital Management (PGDHM) from Savitribai Phule Pune University,
 2019
- Bachelor of Engineering in Electronics from University of Mumbai, 2000

PROJECTS

- Successfully completed a project to create a Terminal Library Management System in Python.
- Worked on building a Pharmacy Inventory in Python using Binary Tree.
- Developed an Employee Register Application using Django Rest Framework and SQLite3 database, a Portfolio page using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and successfully migrated the same using Flask microframework and SQLite database. Also, implemented the same using React Frontend Framework.
- Developed a Healthcare Management System using Django REST framework, HTML, CSS with MySQL as database.

TECHNICAL EXPERTISE

- Products TLM Reconciliations Suite, TLM Process Automation
- Programming Languages Python, JavaScript
- Frameworks and libraries Django, Django Rest Framework, Flask, Python libraries for Machine Learning
- Data Visualization Tableau, Power BI
- Database Oracle, MS SQL Server, My SQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB
- Cloud deployment
 AWS, Heroku
- Version Control Git
- Domain Capital Markets (Equity), Treasury Confirmations (FX and MM), Reconciliations, Healthcare Administration.

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Project planning, solution design, product configuration, data analysis, workflow automation,
 Business Requirement Documentation, Use case and Functional Requirement Documentation.

- Agile Methodologies, Implementation, Testing, Business Analysis, SDLC
- Excellent verbal and written communication skills.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Byte Academy, Bangalore

Intern (Sep 2021 – Nov 2021)

I have recently completed an internship with Byte Academy for their client Randstad which is one of the largest global HR services firms.

I was responsible for providing the analytics required to create a Salary Trends Report that highlights hiring trends and roles in demand across industries, functions, and cities in India for the year 2021.

It involved cleaning of the data that was scraped from various job portals using Python Regex, taking care of duplicate records, creating functions to map Industry, Function and Skill buckets based on the Organization and skills, respectively, using Mapping Master files and analysing the data for discrepancies using Pandas.

The data extracted was then used to create the Salary Trends Report that would provide insights about highest paying jobs, skills across various functions and industries and cities.

SmartStream Technologies, Bangalore

Project Manager (Northern Trust Bank) (Jan 2016-Mar 2017)

- Leading, mentoring, training a team of 6 for implementation of critical reconciliation processes in TLM Reconciliations Premium along with project planning, costing, risk analysis and mitigation
- Consulting with stakeholders, providing effective solutions to problems including escalation, follow-through, dissemination of workarounds leading to timely closure by maintaining Issue Trackers, Project Plans.

Consultant (ANZ, Deutsche Bank, HSBC) (Apr 2012-Dec 2015)

- Designing, building, testing, and delivering a solution for automation of Internal Employee
 Funding system using TLM Control and Exception Management Process Integration system using
 TLM and PEGA for ANZ.
- Delivering solutions and providing end user training for migration of reconciliations from TLM 2.1 to 2.7 for Deutsche Bank.
- Implementation and delivery of TLM Treasury Confirmations Solution for HSBC.

SmartStream Technologies, Mumbai

Team Lead (Credit Suisse, J P Morgan, Nomura) (Nov 2007-Mar 2012)

- Design and implementation of TLM Cash Management solution using TLM Control and TLM Reconciliations to manage Cash Accounts for Credit Suisse. This involved building new features and providing various user interfaces and backend functionality for automated operations.
- Preparing Business and Functional Documents, Design and Building of a Static Data utility to automate Static Data creation using a combination of HTML, JavaScript, and Stored Procedures to create dashboards.
- Document, Build and Deliver Client Segregation and Prime Broker Reconciliation solutions for Nomura on TLM Reconciliations.

Senior Product Specialist (Lehman Brothers, Citibank, J P Morgan) (Feb 2003-Oct 2007)

- Analysing requirements, creating Business Requirement Documents, consulting with business analysts and end users to automate cash, stock and trade reconciliations for Lehman Brothers using TLM Reconciliations and help them to migrate from SSR to TLM.
- Designing, building, documenting Client Money solution for Citibank which required me to work extensively on Sybase, creating stored procedures, functions for dashboards and complex data manipulation, creating a thin client for end users with configuration using TLM Process Automation.
- Designing and building an Exception Management Workflow using TLM Process Automation for JP Morgan, London by working with their Back Office, Middle Office, and Front Office User Teams to understand the working and to improve the manual processes using a combination of proprietary software and database management.

Glotech Solutions Inc, Mumbai

Quality Assurance Professional (Wells Fargo) (Dec 2000-Jan 2003)

 Implementation of TLM Process Automation to build a Straight Through Processing (STP) Solution for Wells Fargo, Creation of SWIFT Data Field Dictionaries (DFDs) of various SWIFT Message Types (15022 and 7775) and successful execution of POC's and Demo's for prospective clients along with the pre-sales and sales team.

PERSONAL DETAILS

• Address: Sacred Heart Town, Wanowrie, Pune

• Languages: English, Hindi, Marathi, Malayalam